当我躺在退伍军人医院里
When I was lying there in the VA hospital,
面对着我一生最大的不幸
with a big hole blown through the middle of my life,
我开始做一些有关于飞翔的梦
I started having these dreams of flying.
自由地飞翔
I was free.
但是 你总有醒来的一刻
Sooner or later, though, you always have to wake up.
假如你有钱的话 他们可以帮你把脊髓医好
They can fix a spinal, if you got the money,
但单靠那点退伍军人的抚恤金
but not on vet benefits,
根本不可能做到
not in this economy.
一次VA检查再加12美元
A VA check and 12 bucks.
你只有一杯咖啡
will get you a cup of coffee.
我就是他们所称的轮候
I'm what they call… waitlisted.
那些孟加拉虎
The Bengal Tiger,
灭绝了差不多一个世纪后又回来了
extinct for over a century is making a comeback.
那些在北京动物园的克隆品
These cloned tiger cubs at the Beijing Zoo.
已经是那个物种剩下的最后几只了
are the latest of a number of species.
他们在最近五年又被克隆回来了
that have been cloned back into existence in the past five years.
我为了锻炼自己而加入了海军陆战队
I became a marine for the hardship. To be hammered on the anvil of life.
我一直告诉自己别人做到的事我也一定能做到
I told myself I can pass any test a man can pass.
杰克！杰克！杰克！杰克！
Jake! Jake! Jake! Jake! Jake!
让我们直话直说吧
Let's get it straight, upfront.
我不想要你的同情
I don't want your pity.
你想要一个公平的交易 你来错星球了
You want a fair deal, you're on the wrong planet.
弱肉强食
The strong prey on the weak.
事实就是这样
That's just the way things are.
而且没人会在意
And nobody does a damn thing.
滚开！ 离他远点！
Get off! Get off of him!
我只是想为了应该奋斗的事而奋斗
All I ever wanted in my sorry-ass life was a single thing worth fighting for.
我希望你知道
I hope you realized.
你刚又令你自己失去了一个顾客
you just lost yourself a customer.
娘娘腔
Candy-ass bitch.
如果不下雨的话 我们就不训练
If it ain't raining, we ain't training.
- 那看起来不像他 - 是他
- It doesn't look like him. - It's him.
你是杰克·萨利？
You Jake Sully?
离远点 你扫了我的兴
Step off. You're ruining my good mood.
是关于你哥哥的
It's about your brother.
我们在找汤米·萨利
We're looking for Sully, T.
我们到了
In there.
天啊 汤米
Jesus, Tommy.
弱肉强食
The strong prey on the weak.
有个拿枪的家伙结束了他的生命
A guy with a knife took all Tommy would ever be.
只为了他口袋里的几张钞票
for the paper in his wallet.
我心里充满了伤感
The concern of the suits was touching.
你的哥哥参与了我们一个重要投资计划
Your brother represented a significant investment.
我们想找你接手完成他的合同
We'd like to talk to you about taking over his contract.
因为你们有着相同的基因组
And since your genome is identical to his,
所以我们认为你可以继续他的任务
you could step into his shoes,
可以这么说
so to speak.
这将会是一个新的开始
It'd be a fresh start.
在一个新的世界
on a new world.
你会改头换面
You could do something important. You can make a difference.
报酬也很丰厚
And the pay is good.
非常丰厚
Very good.
汤米才是科学家 我不是
Tommy was the scientist, not me.
他是那种可以飞到数光年远的外太空去
He was the one who wanted to get shot light-years out in space.
寻找真理的那种人
to find the answers.
而我只是个笨蛋
Me, I was just another dumb grunt.
飞向一个自己将会后悔前往的地方
getting sent someplace he was gonna regret.
人在低温睡眠时不会作梦
In cryo, you don't dream at all.
这种感觉不像是过了六年
It doesn't feel like six years.
比较像是喝了五杯龙舌兰后打过一架的宿醉
More like a fifth of tequila and an ass-kicking.
我们到了吗？
Are we there yet?
嗯 我们到了 帅哥
Yeah, we're there, sunshine.
我们到了
We're there.
你已经在低温睡眠状态中
You've been in cryo.
躺了五年九个月二十二天
for five years, nine months and 22 days.
你会感到饥饿 也会感到虚弱
You will be hungry. You will be weak.
如果你觉得恶心想吐 请使用呕吐袋
If you feel nausea, please use the sacks provided for your convenience.
工作人员会非常感谢你的
The staff thanks you in advance.
前面就是潘多拉星球
Up ahead was Pandora.
从小就听说过它 但是从没想过会去那里
You grew up hearing about it, but I never figured I'd be going there.
「女战神号」航天飞机 回复…
Valkyrie 1-6, copy…
「女战神号」航天飞机
Valkyrie 1-6,
你可以在2-2-4-niner脱轨
you are clear for de-orbit burn at 2-2-4-niner.
收到 准备在2-2-4-niner脱轨
Copy, Venture Star. Go for de-orbit burn at 2-2-4-niner.
- 戴上滤气面罩！ 都戴上！ - 戴上滤气面罩！ 都戴上！
- Exo-packs on! Let's go! Exo-packs on! - Exo-packs on! Let's go!
你们得记住 没有滤气面罩
Remember, people, you lose that mask,
你将会在二十秒后昏厥 四分钟内死亡！
you're unconscious in 20 seconds, you're dead in four minutes!
谁都不准今天给我死了！
Let's nobody be dead today!
那会让我的报告很难看
Looks very bad on my report.
地狱大门塔台 飞行器准备降落
Hell's Gate tower, this is TAV 1-6 on approach.
穿越外界线 矿场进入视线
Crossing outer marker. Mine is in sight.
松开安全带 拿好你们的东西
Harnesses off! Get your packs!
都给我准备好 快点！动作快！
Put it together, let's go! Let's go!
一分钟 准备
Harnesses off! One minute!
舷梯落下后
When that ramp comes down,
直接进去基地里 别停下来！
go directly into the base. Do not stop!
直接跑过去 听我的口令！
Go straight inside. Wait for my mark!
走 走 走 走！ 快点出去！
Go, go, go, go! Get out of there!
继续向前！ 快走 不要停下来！
Keep moving! Let's go, let's go!
没有所谓的前海军陆战队员
There's no such thing as an ex-Marine.
你也许退役了
You may be out,
但你永远不会忘记军人那股精神
but you never lose the attitude.
快点 特殊人士 别让我等你
Let's go, special case! Do not make me wait for you!
喔 喔 小妞们
Well, well, ladies.
看看这群菜鸟
Look at all this fresh meat!
在地球上 这些人都是军人 陆战队员
Back on Earth, these guys were Army dogs, Marines,
为自由而战
fighting for freedom.
小心点 轮椅男！
Look out, hot rod!
但在这里 他们只是佣兵
But out here they're just hired guns,
拿钱替私人企业办事
taking the money, working for the company.
瞧那家伙
Check this out, man.
来吃闲饭的
Meals on wheels.
不会吧 这也太扯了
Oh, man, that is just wrong.
二十分钟后会有两个人有空！
I got two guys free in about 20 minutes!
知道了 我需要他们！
Got it! Need them!
你们已经不在堪萨斯了
You're not in Kansas anymore.
这里是「潘多拉」星球 女士们 先生们
You are on Pandora, ladies and gentlemen.
你们要时时刻刻记住这一点
Respect that fact every second of every day.
如果世界上真的有地狱
If there is a hell,
在游历过潘多拉后你可能会想去地狱休假
you might want to go there for some R&R after a tour on Pandora.
在那道围墙后面
Out there, beyond that fence,
任何活的东西 不论是天上飞的
every living thing that crawls,
还是地上爬的 土里钻的
flies or squats in the mud.
都想把你生吞活剥地吃了
wants to kill you and eat your eyes for Jujubes.
这里有一个原生的种族
We have an indigenous population of humanoids.
我们称其为「纳威人」
called the Na'vi.
他们喜欢在弓箭上涂上一种神经毒素
They're fond of arrows dipped in a neurotoxin.
那玩意可以让你的心跳在一分钟内停止
that'll stop your heart in one minute.
他们有着天生的强化碳纤维骨骼
And they have bones reinforced with naturally occurring carbon fiber.
非常难杀死
They are very hard to kill.
做为你们的安保长官
As head of security,
我的职责就是保障你们每一个人都活着
it is my job to keep you alive.
但这是不可能的
I will not succeed.
至少不可能成功保住每一个人
Not with all of you.
如果你们想活命
If you wish to survive,
就一定要有坚毅的态度
you need to cultivate a strong mental attitude.
你们必须遵守规则
You've got to obey the rules.
「潘多拉规则」
Pandora rules.
规则一
Rule number one…
什么都比不上这种老掉牙的训话
There's nothing like an old-school safety brief.
能令人安心
to put your mind at ease.
抱歉 抱歉 杰克 你是杰克
Excuse me. Excuse me. Jake! You're Jake,
对吗 汤米的双胞胎弟弟
right? Tom's brother.
哇 你长得跟他一模一样
Wow! You look just like him.
抱歉 我是诺姆·斯贝尔曼
Sorry, I'm Norm. Spellman.
我曾和他一起接受「阿凡达」计划的训练
I went through avatar training with him.
这是生物实验室
…into the bio-lab.
我们将会在这里待很久的
We're gonna spend a lot of time up here.
嗨 你好 我是诺姆 阿凡达操作员
Hey! How you doing? Norm, avatar driver.
- 你好 - 嘿
- Hi. - Hey.
这里是连结室
Link… Here's the link room right here.
我们会在这里连结上阿凡达
This is where we're connecting to the avatar.
我和诺姆会在这里
Me and Norm are here to drive.
远程控制这些叫「阿凡达」的生命体
these remotely controlled bodies called avatars.
这是一种用人类基因结合
And they're grown from human DNA mixed.
纳威人的基因培育出来的生命体
with the DNA of the natives.
- 嘿 欢迎 - 嘿
- Hey. Welcome. - Hey.
欢迎来到潘多拉 很高兴你们能来
Welcome to Pandora. Good to have you.
谢了
Thanks.
哇哦 他们真大
Damn! They got big.
是的 在我们飞行时他们已经完全成熟了
Yeah, they fully mature on the flight out.
看来本体感知模拟器运作非常顺利
So the proprioceptive sims seem to work really well.
没错 他们肌肉相当发达
Yeah, they've got great muscle tone.
我们还得花几个小时为他们准备
It'll take us a few hours to get them decanted,
不过明天你们就能操控了
but you guys can take them out tomorrow.
你的在那里
There's yours.
嗨 诺姆·斯贝尔曼博士
Hey. Dr. Norm Spellman.
麦克斯·佩特尔博士 很高兴见到你
Dr. Max Patel. Great to meet you.
很高兴见到你
Good to meet you, yeah.
长得很像他
Looks like him.
长得也很像你
No, it looks like you.
杰克 这是你的阿凡达了
This is your avatar now, Jake.
这个计划的概念是
And the concept is.
每位操作员都能连结自己专属的阿凡达
that every driver is matched to his own avatar,
他们的神经系统就能协调一致
so that their nervous systems are in tune,
资源开发管理总署之类的
or something.
这是他们找我的原因
Which is why they offered me the gig,
因为我能连结汤米的阿凡达
because I can link with Tommy's avatar,
阿凡达的造价惊人
which is insanely expensive.
这样做对吗
Is this right?
我把所有事全部录下来就对了吗？
I just say whatever to the video log?
对 你要习惯记录所有的事情
Yeah, we gotta get in the habit of documenting everything.
任何我们看到的 感觉到的
You know, what we see, what we feel.
这是科学研究的一部分
It's all part of the science.
详细的观察对研究很有帮助
And good science is good observation.
而且这样可以
Plus it'll help to.
让你在今后的六年里避免精神错乱
keep you sane for the next six years.
随便啦
All right. Whatever.
那么
So…
我在这里
Well, here I am,
进行科学研究
doing science.
操作员要出来了
They're coming out!
注意 操作员出舱中
Attention. Drivers coming out of link.
喔 天哪
Oh, God.
她的工作服呢？ 谁看见她的工作服？
Where's the lab coat? Where's the lab coat?
谁拿走我的该死的香烟啦？
Who's got my goddamn cigarette?
各位 我这样子有不对吗？
Guys! What's wrong with this picture?
谢谢！
Thank you!
格蕾丝·奥古斯汀是一位传奇人物
Grace Augustine is a legend.
她是阿凡达计划的带头人 她写了本书
She's the head of the Avatar Program. She wrote the book,
我是说那本有关潘多拉植物学的著作
I mean, literally wrote the book on Pandoran botany.
那是因为她对植物的兴趣可能比对人还多
Well, that's 'cause she likes plants better than people.
这位就是了 灰姑娘参加完舞会回来了
Here she is, Cinderella back from the ball.
格蕾丝我来给你介绍一下
Grace, I'd like you to meet.
诺姆·斯贝尔曼和杰克·萨利
Norm Spellman and Jake Sully.
诺姆 听说你很优秀
Norm. I hear good things about you.
你的纳威话学得怎么样了？
How's your Na'vi?
愿万灵之母…
May the All Mother…
祝福我们的初次见面
…smile upon our first meeting.
还不错 但太拘谨了点
Not bad. You sound a little formal.
我学了五年…
I studied for five years…
但还有很多东西要学
…but there is much to learn.
格蕾丝 这位是杰克·萨利
Grace? This is Jake Sully.
夫人
Ma'am.
我知道你是谁 我要的是你哥哥 不是你
Yeah, yeah. I know who you are, and I don't need you. I need your brother.
知道吗 那位已经为这个项目
You know, the PhD who trained.
培训整整三年的哲学博士？
for three years for this mission?
他已经死了
He's dead.
我知道这给所有人带来了巨大的麻烦
I know it's a big inconvenience for everyone.
- 你在实验室受过什么训练 - 解剖过一次青蛙
- How much lab training have you had? - I dissected a frog once.
看吧 看吧 他们现在摆明就是要整我们
You see? You see? I mean, they're just pissing on us.
都懒得遮掩
without even the courtesy of calling it rain.
- 我要去找塞弗里奇 - 不 格蕾丝
- I'm going to Selfridge. - No, Grace,
我不认为这是好主意
I don't think that's a good idea.
不行 这简直是在胡闹
No, man, this is such bullshit!
我要去给他一点颜色瞧瞧
I'm gonna kick his corporate butt.
他休想在我的部门搞鬼
He has no business sticking his nose in my department.
明天早上八点到这里 注意一下你的用词
Here tomorrow, 0800. Try and use big words.
蝎子二号攻击机 这是地狱之门塔台
Scorpion Two-Hotel, Hell's Gate tower.
你们可以从南面起飞了
You are cleared for south departure.
使用Ｄ跑道滑行 身份确认
Hover taxi, Delta runway. Squawk ident.
- 看见没？ - 看见了 长官
- You see that? - Yes, sir.
你没有 你在看监视器
No, you didn't. You were looking at the monitor.
我爱死这支球杆了 罗尼！
I love this putter, Ronnie!
我爱死这支球杆了
I love this putter.
帕克 我原本以为这只是一时的疏忽
Parker, you know, I used to think it was benign neglect,
但是我现在明白了 你根本就是在故意整我
but now I see that you're intentionally screwing me.
格蕾丝 你知道 我很爱跟你小聊一下
Grace, you know, I enjoy our little talks.
我需要的是科学家 不是退役的陆战队员
I need a researcher. Not some jarhead dropout.
是吗 我倒觉得我们能找到他算很幸运的
Well, actually, I thought we got lucky with him.
- 幸运 - 对
- Lucky? - Yeah.
这算哪门子的幸运？
How is this in any way lucky?
幸亏你的科学家有个双胞胎弟弟
Lucky your guy had a twin brother,
更庆幸的是 还好他不是什么牙医师之类的
and lucky that brother wasn't some oral hygienist or something.
而是一位很有用处的陆战队员
A Marine we can use.
我已经指派他作你小组的护卫
I'm assigning him to your team as security escort.
我现在最不需要的就是
The last thing I need is.
多一个喜欢扣板机的白痴在我这里！
another trigger-happy moron out there!
听着 听着 你的任务就是要赢得
Look, look, you're supposed to be winning the hearts.
那些土著的信任
and the minds of the natives.
这难道不是
Isn't that the whole point.
你那可笑的玩偶剧存在的唯一原因吗？
of your little puppet show?
你装扮得像他们 讲话也像他们
If you look like them and you talk like them,
那他们也应该就会开始信任我们
then they'll start trusting us.
我们帮他们建立学校 教他们说人类语言
We build them a school, we teach them English,
结果呢 这么多年过去了？
but after, what, how many years?
关系却越搞越糟
Relations with the indigenous are only getting worse.
那就是因为你用机关枪对着他们的结果
Yeah, that tends to happen when you use machine guns on them.
好 跟我来
Right. Come here.
我不能 我不能
I can't… I can't…
这是我们来这里的原因 超导矿石
This is why we're here. Unobtanium.
因为这颗小小的灰色石头
Because this little gray rock sells.
每公斤价值两千万美元
for 20 million a kilo.
这就是唯一的原因
That's the only reason.
就是这个靠东西养活我们这里所有的人
It's what pays for the whole party.
就是靠它来支撑你的科学研究
It's what pays for your science.
现在那群土著 正在防碍着我们的采矿作业
Now, those savages are threatening our whole operation,
我们正处于随时会开战的时刻
we're on the brink of war,
而你的任务就是
and you're supposed to be.
帮我们找一个外交途径的解决办法
finding a diplomatic solution.
所以你就尽你所能 给我拿出个成果来吧
So use what you've got, and get me some results.
你有多长时间的操作经验？
So, how much link time have you logged?
- 大约五百二十个小时 - 很好
- About 520 hours. - That's good.
你在那里 你在这里
You're in there. You're here.
你有多长时间的操作经验
How much have you logged?
零 但我有读过说明书
Zip. But I read a manual.
你不是在说笑的吧
Tell me you're joking.
这真酷
This is cool.
出发
Let's go.
不用 我自己可以搞定
Don't. I got this.
所以你认为你可以不经过任何训练
So you just figured you'd come out here,
来到人类已知的最恶劣的环境里
to the most hostile environment known to man,
既没参加过任何训练也没看过它是怎么运行的
with no training of any kind, and see how it went?
你脑袋里到底在想什么啊？
What was going through your head?
也许我只是讨厌别人一直告诉我什么不能做
Maybe I was sick of doctors telling me what I couldn't do.
生命反应良好
Biometrics are good.
三号连接舱已准备就绪
Link three is ready.
手臂放在里面 手放进去 头躺下
Keep your arms in, hands in, head down.
往下 放轻松 脑袋放空就好
Down. Just relax and let your mind go blank.
这对你来说应该不难
That shouldn't be hard for you.
闭上你的
Kiss the darkest part of my lily white…
启动连接
Initiate link.
启动程序 三号
Run sequence unit three. Go.
启动中
Launching.
得到第一份数据
I have the first congruency.
- 好漂亮的大脑 非常活跃 - 真没想到
- That's a gorgeous brain. Nice activity. - Go figure.
同步率 40%
Phase-Iock 40%.
好 我也要进去了
All right. Going in.
我要进入四号舱
I'm going in in four.
同步率 99% 连结稳定
Phase-Iock 99%. Link is stable.
他进去了 杰克 听得到我说话吗
He's in. Jake, can you hear me?
听得到我说话吗？ 杰克
Can you hear me, Jake?
瞳孔反应情况良好
Pupillary reflex is good.
听觉反应正常 感觉怎样？ 杰克
Pinna response normal. How you feeling, Jake?
嘿 你们好
Hey, guys.
杰克 欢迎进入你的新身体
Welcome to your new body, Jake.
很好
Good!
杰克 我们慢慢来
Yeah, we're gonna take this nice and easy, Jake.
- 用你的拇指碰其他的手指 - 好
- And touch your thumb to your fingers. - Yeah.
- 用拇指碰其他的手指 - 没问题
- Thumb to your fingers. - No problem.
做得不错 看来你还记得怎么做
That's good. I can see you can remember that one.
- 知道了 - 如果你想坐起来
- Got it. - Well, if you want to sit up,
- 就坐起来吧 - 很好 没关系慢慢来 杰克
- that's fine. - Okay, good. Just take it.
镇静剂没有任何副作用 很好
nice and slow, Jake. Good. Okay, well, no truncal ataxia, that's good.
你有觉得头晕或不舒服吗 动动你的脚趾
Are you feeling lightheaded or dizzy at all? You're wiggling your toes!
- 很好 杰克 - 太好了
- Good. Good, Jake. - That's great.
运动神经控制正常
Distal motor control is good. Good, Jake.
有没有感到哪里发麻或者疼痛？
Are you feeling any numbness or pain?
- 很好 杰克 - 等一下 现在 别着急
That's great, Jake. Hold on, now.
慢一点 不要操之过急 好吗
Take it easy. Don't get ahead of yourself, okay?
我们还要测试一些感官反射动作
There's a few more sensory motor reflex tests we need to run,
- 所以要慢慢来 - 等等
- so take it easy. - Wait.
- 杰克 - 坐下 杰克
- Jake. - Sit down, Jake.
杰克！ 听我说
Jake! Listen to me. Jake!
- 杰克！ 你得坐下 - 没事
- I need you to sit down. Jake! - It's okay.
- 听我说 - 没事 我控制得住
- Buddy, listen to me. - It's all good. I got this.
杰克 你必须立刻坐下
Jake, you need to sit down right now.
大家快把他弄回床上
Guys, get him back on the gurney now.
听我说 为了你的安全起见
Listen to me. For your own safety,
你必须坐下来
you need to sit down.
你需要时间适应你的阿凡达身体 喔！ 杰克！
You need time to adjust to the avatar… Whoa! Jake!
- 杰克 小心尾巴 - 耶！
- God, Jake, watch your tail. - Yeah!
给他注射镇定剂！ 一千毫克镇定剂！ 快点！
Sedate! Sedate him! A thousand milligrams of Supitocam! Stat!
各位！ 各位！ 小心！ 小心！
Guys! Guys! Whoa! Whoa!
参照说明
By the numbers.
- 杰克 别这样 - 听我说
- Jake. Come on. - Jake! Listen to me.
你还不习惯你的阿凡达
You're not used to your avatar body.
- 这很危险 - 这感觉太棒了
- This is dangerous. - This is great.
杰克
Jake? Jake, listen to me.
别闹了 他们会把你麻醉的
Come on. They're gonna put you out.
诺姆 你得坐下
Norm, sit down.
不 不 不 我得弄掉这些线
No, no. I gotta get out of these leads.
该死的 快把他俩弄回来
God damn it! Bring them home!
- 诺姆 不要擅自离开 - 你还没准备好！
- Norm! Do not leave control! - You're not ready for it!
来啊 看你有什么本事
Oh, come on, you ain't got no skills.
差一点
So close!
我甚至不需要防守你
I don't even have to play defense on it.
嘿 你们好 嘿
Hey, guys. Hey.
没关系 我去把他抓回来
It's okay, I'll get him.
杰克 你必须回来
Jake, you have to come back!
杰克 不好意思
Jake! Jake! Excuse me.
- 小心 - 对不起！
- Watch it! - Sorry!
快点
Come on!
杰克 你不能随便奔跑的！
Jake! We're not supposed to be running!
- 天啦 对不起 - 小心点！
- Jeez! Sorry. - Watch it!
嘿 陆战队的！
Hey, Marine!
糟了
Damn.
格蕾丝？
Grace?
不然你还以为是谁？ 笨蛋
Well, who'd you expect, numbnuts?
别发呆
Think fast.
动作控制看来很好
Motor control's looking good.
大家安静下来 好了 熄灯了
Come on, everybody, quiet down! All right, gang, lights out.
露易丝 快一点
Come on, Louise, chop-chop.
嘿 嘿 嘿！
Hey, hey, hey!
别玩那玩意 会弄瞎你的
Don't play with that, you'll go blind.
真是诡异
That's kind of freaky.
快离开吧
Come on. Scat.
晚安
Good night.
关灯啦 孩子们 晚餐时候见
Lights out! See you at dinner, kiddies.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
- 你还好吧 没事吧 - 我没事
- You okay? You all right? - Yeah, I'm okay.
我叫楚迪 专门负责接送科学家
I'm Trudy. I fly all the science sorties.
这是我的宝贝儿
And this here is my baby.
稍等一下
Hold on a second.
嘿 温弗利 快点装好
Hey, Wainfleet! Get it done!
我们九点就要出发
We bounce at zero-nine.
已经在弄了 上尉
Yeah, I'm on it, capitaine!
发射器还是有点松
Vine strike's still loose.
你们装了不少重武器啊
You guys are packing some heavy gear.
看着点
Watch it!
那是因为我们并非唯一会在天上飞的东西
Yeah, that's 'cause we're not the only thing flying around out there.
或是最具威胁性的
Or the biggest.
我们现在缺个人手 你就先担任侧翼机枪手吧
I'm gonna need you on a door gun. I'm a man short.
我还以为你不会要求呢
I thought you'd never ask.
那就是你要见的人 咱们飞机上见
There's your man. See you on the flight line.
你找我吗？ 上校
You wanted to see me, Colonel?
这里的低重力会让你变得怠惰
This low gravity'll make you soft.
你要是变得怠惰了
You get soft,
潘多拉的生物会不费吹灰之力地把你干掉
Pandora will shit you out dead with zero warning.
我看过你的档案了 下士
I pulled your record, Corporal.
委内瑞拉丛林 那还真是个凶险的地方
Venezuela, that was some mean bush.
但跟这里比 简直天差地远
Nothing like this here, though.
你很有种 小子 敢跑到这里来
You got some heart, kid, showing up in this neighborhood.
我想不过就是另一个地狱吧
I figured it's just another hellhole.
我自己曾经也是个侦查兵
I was First Recon myself.
比你早个几年 搞不好更早
A few years ahead of you. Well, maybe more than a few.
去了尼日利亚三次 毫发无伤
Three tours Nigeria, not a scratch.
但来这里？
I come out here?
第一天就中奖了
Day one.
是不是觉得我像个刚剃了头的菜鸟
Think I felt like a shavetail louie?
等当时我要是回地球去
Yeah. They could fix me up,
他们就可以帮我动手术
if I rotated back.
让我恢复帅气的样貌
Yeah, and make me pretty again.
但是你知道吗？ 我更喜欢现在这个样子
But you know what? I kind of like it.
它可以随时提醒我 外面有些什么凶险玩意
It reminds me every day what's waiting out there.
阿凡达计划是个无聊的笑话
The Avatar Program is a bad joke.
养了一群没用的科学家
Bunch of limp-dick science majors.
不过 这无非是另一种机会
However, it does present an opportunity both timely and unique.
- 后方清空！ - 清空！
- Clear! - Clear!
一个伪装成阿凡达的侦查兵
A recon gyrene in an avatar body.
真是个绝妙的组合
That's a potent mix.
令我兴奋地连鸡皮疙瘩都起来了
Give me the goose bumps.
这样的一个陆战队员的确能给我提供不少
Such a Marine could provide the intel I need,
实地的情报
right on the ground.
最深入的情报
Right in the hostiles' camp.
听着 萨利 我要你从内部了解这帮土著
Look, Sully. I want you to learn these savages from the inside.
我要你赢得他们的信任
I want you to gain their trust.
我必须知道怎样才能让他们就范
I need to know how to force their cooperation.
或是如何逼他们就范 如果他们不肯屈服
or hammer them hard if they won't.
那我还是奥古斯汀小组的成员吗？
Am I still with Augustine?
台面上是
On paper.
你可以和那些科学家一起做研究
Yeah, you walk like one of her science pukes,
你也可以跟他们闲话家常
you quack like one,
但你是向我报告
but you report to me.
你能做得到吗 小子？
Can you do that for me, son?
可以 长官
Hell, yeah, sir.
这样就对了
Well, all right, then.
孩子 我会照顾自己人的
Son, I take care of my own.
你拿到我需要的东西后
You get me what I need,
等你回来时我会让你重新站起来
I'll see to it you get your legs back when you rotate home.
用你自己的腿
Your real legs.
听起来很诱人 长官
That sounds real good, sir.
- 连结准备就绪！ - 同步率40%
- Link's ready! - Phase-Iock 40%.
你不许出声 让诺姆负责说话
Just keep your mouth shut and let Norm do the talking.
第五阶段融合完成 同步率90%
I have five congruencies. Phase-Iock 90%.
三号舱准备就绪
Link three ready.
好 我要进去了
All right, I'm going in.
斯塔姆兽就在你右面
Sturmbeest herd coming up on your right.
知道了！ 谢谢
Got it! Thanks.
这些家伙就像是公牛 但又带有些温柔
Looks like a bull, a dozen cows and some juveniles.
关掉引擎 我们会在这里停留一会
Shut it down. We're gonna stay a while.
- 诺姆 你的背包 - 背包
- Norm! Your pack. - Pack.
你就待在飞机旁吧
Stay with the ship.
有一个拿着枪的白痴就够了
One idiot with a gun is enough.
你说了算 博士
You the man, Doc.
潘多拉狐猴 没有攻击性的
Prolemuris. They're not aggressive.
放轻松点 陆战队的 你搞得我也紧张了
Relax, Marine. You're making me nervous.
他们如何知道我们来到这里？
So, how will they know we're here?
我很确定他们现在正在监视着我们
I'm sure they're watching us right now.
这里曾经是我们建的学校
This was our school.
现在这里只是一个贮藏库了
Now it's just… storage.
那些孩子都是非常聪明的
The kids were so bright.
热衷于学习
Eager to learn.
他们的人类语言甚至不用我教也学得很快
They picked up English faster than I could teach it.
那么拿一些酸碱检测器
So, we'll take a couple of these Ph monitors…
和探泥针
…and a soil probe.
那边的小黄色箱子 有个旧的显微镜
That little yellow case back there. The old microscope.
这个
Here.
哦 对 我很爱这个
Oh, yeah. I love this one.
那些刺蝠把它们都搞到地上了
The stingbats knocked them down.
我一直都希望能有孩子回到这里 再读读它们
I keep hoping someone will come back in and read them.
他们为什么不回来？
Why don't they come back?
奥玛蒂卡亚族部落
The Omaticaya…
他们已经精通了我们的语言
learned as much about us as they needed to.
这里发生了什么事？
What happened here?
你还打算用这装备来帮我们吗？
Are you going to help us with this gear?
我们还有很多事要忙
We've got a lot to do.
- 别停下 诺姆 - 你们俩跟紧了！
- Keep moving, Norm. - Keep up, guys!
- 那么就开始啦 - 扫描中
- And here I go. - Scanning.
怎么会这么快？
Wow! It's that fast?
- 很惊人 是吧？ - 是啊
- Amazing, isn't it? - Yeah.
这就是信号传导
So, that is signal transduction from this root.
从这个树根传到旁边的那个树根
to the root of the tree next to it. So,
我们应该采集一个样本
we should take a sample.
好 样本
Okay. Sample.
反应速度那么快 我觉得这里可能有电流
You know, it's probably electrical, based on the speed of the reaction.
诺姆 你的口水污染到样本了
Norm, you've contaminated the sample with your saliva.
喔 对不起
Right.
再采一个样本
So, here I go.
别开枪 别开枪 你会把它惹毛的
Don't shoot. Don't shoot, you'll piss him off.
我已经把它惹毛了
It's already pissed off.
杰克 它皮太厚 子弹打不穿 相信我
Jake, that armor's too thick. Trust me.
它只是在宣示它的地盘
It's a territorial threat display.
千万别跑 否则他会冲上来的
Do not run, or he'll charge.
那我要做啥 跟它跳舞吗？
So, what do I do, dance with it?
待在原地别动
Just hold your ground.
来啊 看你有什么能耐？
Yeah? Come on! What you got?
来啊 看谁厉害 这就对了
Oh, yeah. Who's bad? That's right.
这样就对了 畜牲
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about, bitch.
对啦 滚回去找你的妈咪吧
That's right, get your punk ass back to mommy.
就这些能耐啊 快滚吧
Yeah? Yeah, you got nothing. You keep running.
要不再多叫几个同伴过来？
Yeah, and why don't you bring back some of your friends, huh?
糟了
Oh, shit.
怎么应付这种 跑 还是不跑？
So what about this one? Run? Don't run? What?
跑 当然要跑啦
Run! Definitely run!
我们今天只能到此为止了
I'm gonna have to call it, guys.
上校有命令不许夜间飞行的
We're not allowed to run night ops. Colonel's orders.
对不起 博士 他只能靠自己撑到早上了
I'm sorry, Doc, he's just gonna have to hang on till morning.
他撑不到明天早上的
He won't make it till morning.
我没那时间陪你们耗整晚
I don't have all goddamn night.
来啊！ 来啊！
Come on! Come on!
等等 别扔
Hey, wait. Don't!
这下好了
Great.
我知道你可能听不懂我在说什么
Look, I know you probably don't understand this,
但是谢谢你
but thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这真让人印象深刻
That was pretty impressive.
要是没有你 我早就没命了 这真是
I would have been screwed if you hadn't come along. It was…
等一下 你要去那里？
Hey, wait a second. Hey, where you going?
等等我
Wait up!
走慢点
Just… Hey, slow down.
我只是想谢谢你 帮我杀了那些东西
Look, wait up, I just wanted to say thanks for killing those things.
- 该死 - 不要道谢
- Damn! - Don't thank.
杀戮不需要道谢
You don't thank for this.
这实在太可悲了 非常可悲
This is sad. Very sad only.
好吧 好吧 我很抱歉
Okay. Okay. I'm sorry.
不管我做了什么 我很抱歉
Whatever I did, I am sorry.
这都是你的错 它们本来不应该死的
All this is your fault. They did not need to die.
我的错 它们攻击我
My fault? They attacked me.
怎么我倒成了坏人？
How am I the bad guy?
- 是你的错！- 哎 喔
Your fault!
- 就是你的错！- 别激动 别激动
- Your fault! - Easy. Easy.
你就像个婴儿 只会乱叫 不知所措
You're like a baby. Making noise, don't know what to do.
别激动
Easy.
好 好
Fine. Fine.
如果你这么爱你的森林朋友
If you love your little forest friends,
为什么不干脆让它们杀了我
why not let them just kill my ass?
这是什么逻辑？
What's the thinking?
为什么要救你吗？
Why save you?
对 为什么要救我？
Yeah. Yeah, why save me?
你有一颗坚强的心
You have a strong heart.
无畏无惧
No fear.
但是很愚昧 像个孩子一样无知
But stupid! Ignorant like a child.
要是我像个孩子 那么
Well, if I'm like a child, then…
那或许你该教教我
Look, maybe you should teach me.
你们天空人永远都学不会 你们不用心去感受
Sky People cannot learn. You do not See.
那教教我怎么感受啊
Well, then teach me how to See.
- 没有人能够教你如何用心去感受 - 哇
- No one can teach you to See. - Whoa.
瞧 别这样 我们不能多聊聊吗？
Look, come on, can't we talk?
比如说 你在哪里学的人类语言？
Say, where'd you learn to speak English?
奥古斯汀博士的学校？
Dr. Augustine's school?
你真是像个婴儿
You're like a baby.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
你根本就不应该来这里
You should not be here.
好吧 让我跟你一起走
Okay, take me with you.
不行 回去吧
No! Go back.
不要
No.
回去
Go back.
住手
No!
这
What…
它们是什么？
What are they?
灵魂之树的种子
Seeds of the Sacred Tree.
非常纯洁的灵魂
Very pure spirits.
那是怎么回事？
What was that all about?
来
Come.
来啊
Come!
我们要去那里？
Where are we going?
跟我来
Come.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
该死的
Shit!
好的
Okay.
住手 大家冷静一点
Calm people, calm.
苏泰 你这是在干什么？
What are you doing, Tsu'tey?
这些恶魔禁止到这里来
These demons are forbidden here.
出现神迹了
There has been a sign.
必须交由查希克决定
This is a matter for the Tsahik.
把他带走
Bring him.
怎么了吗？
What's going on?
等等 我们走
Wait.
发生什么事了？
What's happening?
嘿！
Hey!
父亲
Father…
我感受到你
…I see you.
这个地球人
This creature…
你为什么把他带到这里来？
…why do you bring him here?
我原本要杀了他
I was going to kill him…
但是我看见艾娃显现神迹
…but there was a sign from Eywa.
我说过
I have said…
不许带梦行者到这里来
…no dreamwalker will come here.
他说什么？
What's he saying?
这个外星人的臭味真令我作呕
His alien smell fills my nose.
他说什么？
Hey, what's he saying?
我的父亲在决定是否要杀了你
My father is deciding whether to kill you.
你的父亲 很高兴见到您 先生
Your father. It's nice to meet you, sir.
放开这个生物 谁都别动他！
Step back!
我来看看这个外星人
I will look at this alien.
她是我母亲
That is Mother.
她是查希克 能够解读艾娃神谕的人
She is Tsahik. The one who interprets the will of Eywa.
谁是艾娃？
Who's Eywa?
你叫什么名字？
What are you called?
杰克·萨利
Jake Sully.
你为什么来到这里？
Why did you come to us?
我是来学习的
I came to learn.
我们曾经试过教导其他天空人
We have tried to teach other Sky People.
但是自满的人是很难去接受别人的教导
It is hard to fill a cup which is already full.
我一点都不自满 相信我
Well, my cup is empty, trust me.
你可以去问奥古斯汀博士
Just ask Dr. Augustine.
我并不是一位科学家
I'm no scientist.
那你又是什么？
What are you?
我曾是个陆战队员 就是
I was a Marine. A…
一名「锅盖头族」的战士
A warrior of the Jarhead clan.
一个战士！
A warrior!
我能轻易就宰了他！
I could kill him easily!
我能轻易就宰了他！ 不行！
I could kill him easily! No!
这是我们第一次遇到梦行者战士
This is the first warrior dreamwalker…
以前从未遇见过
…we have seen.
我们需要多加了解他
We need to learn more about him.
我的女儿
My Daughter…
你将负责教导他学习我们文化
…you will teach him our way…
学习我们的语言和我们的生活方式
…to speak and walk as we do.
为什么是我教 这不公平
Why me? That's not fair…
就这么决定了
It is decided.
我女儿会教你我们的生活方式
My daughter will teach you our ways.
好好学吧 杰克·萨利
Learn well, Jakesully.
然后我们再看看 你是否还有药可治
Then we will see if your insanity can be cured.
晚上好
Good evening.
不用麻烦站起来了
Please don't get up.
借过
Excuse me.
抱歉
Sorry.
嘿 你好吗？
Hey, how you doing?
谢谢你
Thank you.
我说啊 我还不知道你的名字
You know, I don't even know your name.
妮特丽 特 卡哈 莫阿特伊特
Neytiri te Ckaha Mo'at'ite.
又来 可以慢一点吗！
Again, a whole lot slower?
妮特丽
Neytiri.
妮特里
Neytili.
妮特丽
Neytiri.
很高兴认识你 妮特丽
It's nice to meet you, Neytiri.
很好
It's nice.
- 杰克 - 他处于α脑波态 - 杰克
- Jake. - He's in alpha. - Jake!
- 他快醒过来了 - 杰克 杰克
- He's coming out right now. - Jake. Jake!
醒醒 孩子 醒醒 这就对了
Come on back, kid. Come on. That's it.
你终于回来了
There you go. There you go, there you go.
你没事了 你没事了
You're okay. You're okay.
天哪 你投入得就像只吸血扁虱
Damn! You were dug in like a tick.
- 你的阿凡达安全吗 - 他很安全 博士
- Is the avatar safe? - Yeah, Doc.
你们绝对不会相信我去了哪里
And you are not gonna believe where I am.
我们最后看到的是这个海军陆战队员的背影
The last thing we see is this Marine's ass.
消失在森林中
disappearing into the brush.
而那头怒气冲冲的闪雷兽紧追着他的屁股跑
with this angry thanator coming after him.
- 这可不是一般人学得来的 - 真了不起
- Hey, it's not something you can teach. - That is awesome.
不管是什么原因我也无法理解
You know, for reasons I cannot fathom,
为什么奥玛蒂卡亚族选择了你
the Omaticaya have chosen you.
老天爷帮了我们一个大忙
God help us all.
锅盖头族！
"Jarhead clan"?
他们居然信了！
And it worked?
我现在跟他们是一家人了
Hey, I'm practically family.
他们想了解我
They're gonna study me.
而我要学习如何成为他们的一份子
I have to learn to be one of them.
这就叫先发制人 小子
That's called taking the initiative, son.
我真希望能多十个像你这么能干的
I wish I had 10 more like you.
听着 萨利 萨利
Look, Sully. Sully.
试着查出那些蓝猴子到底想要什么
Just find out what the blue monkeys want.
你知道吗
You know,
我们给他们医疗 教育 道路
I mean, we try to give them medicine, education, roads.
但是没用 他们只爱玩泥巴
But no, no, no, they like mud.
那倒是无所谓 不过问题是
And that wouldn't bother me, it's just that they're…
嘿 你能 谁来弄一下 第十二区
Hey, can you… Can somebody just… Sector 12.
好 走 走 走 停 停
Okay, go, go, go, stop. Stop…
够了 停下！ 那是 天哪！
Rich, stop! That's… Jesus!
他们那该死的部落刚好就位于
Their damn village happens to be resting on the richest unobtanium deposit.
方圆两百公里之内 最丰富的矿区上
within 200 klicks in any direction.
看看那些矿藏！
I mean, look at all that cheddar!
- 谁能说服他们离开呢？ - 你说呢
- Well, who gets them to move? - Guess.
要是他们不想离开呢？
What if they won't go?
我敢打赌他们一定会离开的
I'm betting that they will.
好 嘿 听着
Okay, okay, okay, okay, hey. Look. Look.
杀了那些土著的确会很令人难堪
Killing the indigenous looks bad,
但是比起那些媒体的丑闻
but there's one thing that shareholders hate.
股东们更在意的只有一件事
more than bad press,
那就是难看的季度报表
and that's a bad quarterly statement.
这些规矩不是我定的
I didn't make up the rules.
所以帮我找一个能够让他们搬离这里的方法
So just find me a carrot that'll get them to move,
否则的话
otherwise.
我能只能用我们的手段了 明白吗？
it's gonna have to be all stick. Okay?
你有三个月的时间
You got three months.
届时推土机将会到达那里
That's when the 'dozers get there.
我们这不是在浪费时间吗
Well, we're wasting time.
我喜欢这小子
I like this guy.
- 现在 - 好 我们再来一遍
- Guys, right now… - Okay, let's run through them again.
莫娅 龙族之女
Mo'at. Dragon lady.
- 埃图坎 - 埃图康 他是部落的酋长
- Eytucan. - Eytukan. He's the clan leader.
但莫娅是精神领袖 就像萨满
But she's the spiritual leader. Like a shaman.
明白
Got it.
- 苏泰 - 苏泰
- T'su'tey. - Tsu'tey.
- 苏泰 - 他将是下一任的酋长
- Tsu'tey. - He'll be the next clan leader.
- 妮特丽 - 她将是下一任的查希克
- Neytiri. - She'll be the next Tsahik.
他们将会配对
They become a mated pair.
- 那艾娃是谁？ - 艾娃是谁？
- So who's this Eywa? - Who's Eywa?
是他们唯一的神 创造出许多生命的造物者
Only their deity. Their goddess, made up of all living things.
无所不知的神
Everything they know!
你要是接受过训练就不会问这种问题了
You'd know this if you had any training whatsoever.
那是谁正在和酋长的女儿约会
Who's got a date with the chief's daughter?
拜托 那是
Come on. That's…
你们两个别闹了 把这里搞得托儿所似的
Knock it off. It's like kindergarten around here.
妮特丽曾经是我最好的学生
Neytiri was my best student.
她和她姐姐 Sylwanin
She and her sister, Sylwanin.
真是很棒的女孩
Just amazing girls.
我也跟Sylwanin有个约会哦
I got a date with Sylwanin too.
她已经死了
She's dead.
走吧 乡村生活可是很早就开始的
Let's go. Village life starts early.
别做什么太愚蠢的事
Don't do anything unusually stupid.
乖 小伙子
Easy, boy.
潘多拉烈马是母的
Pale is female.
好吧 乖 小姑娘
Okay. Easy, girl.
那就是「萨黑鲁」 心灵连接
That is shahaylu. The bond.
感受她
Feel her.
感受她的心跳 她的呼吸
Feel her heartbeat. Her breath.
感受它健壮的腿
Feel her strong legs.
你可以告诉它要做什么
You may tell her what to do.
用心告诉它
Inside.
现在 告诉它要去那里
For now, say where to go.
往前！
Forward!
你应该离开这里的
You should go away.
不行 你会想我的
No, you'd miss me.
我就知道你会说人类语言
I knew you could speak English.
这个外星人根本学不会任何东西
This alien will learn nothing…
连颗石头都比他知道的多
…a rock sees more…
瞧他那副德性
…look at him.
再试一次
Again.
如果你真想要攻击这里的话
If you want to hit this thing,
那将会非常麻烦
it's gonna be complicated.
你的扫瞄器无法显示它内部的结构
Your scan doesn't show the internal structure.
外围是一圈柱状物
There's an outer row of columns.
非常结实 这里还有第二圈
Real heavy duty. There's a secondary ring here,
里面还有一圈
and an inner ring.
核心部分则是像螺旋形的结构
There's a core structure like a spiral.
那就是为何他们能在树内上下移动
That's how they move up and down.
我们需要准确扫瞄每根支柱的构造
We're gonna need accurate scans on every column.
收到
Roger that.
对于结构你还有什么要提供吗？
What else can you tell us about the structure?
我想这第二圈支柱也是支撑结构
I'm guessing this secondary ring, that's also load-bearing.
- 我们要去那里 - 离开这里
- So where are we going? - Getting out of Dodge.
我可不会让帕克和夸奇插手这里的事
I'm not about to let Selfridge and Quaritch micro-manage this thing.
二十六号哨站有一个移动的连结室
There's a mobile link up at Site 26 we can work out of,
我们可以在山里继续研究
way up in the mountains.
哈利路亚山？
The Hallelujah Mountains?
- 没错 - 你说的是真的吗？
- That's right. - Are you serious?
- 是的 - 太棒了
- Yeah. - Yes!
传说中的潘多拉悬浮山 你
The legendary floating mountains of Pandora.
又没听说过了吧？
Heard of them?
我们快到了
We're getting close.
是啊 看看我的仪器吧
Yeah, look at my instruments.
我们进入电磁旋涡了
Yep. We're in the Flux Vortex.
现在开始目视飞行
We're VFR from here on.
什么是目视飞行？
What's VFR?
就是用你的眼睛来看路
Means you gotta see where you're going.
但我什么都看不见啊
You can't see anything.
没错 很夸张吧
Exactly. Ain't that a bitch?
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
瞧你们那副表情
You should see your faces.
感谢您搭乘潘多拉航空
Thank you for flying Air Pandora.
是什么维持着他们漂浮？
So what does hold them up?
格蕾丝向我解释过
Grace explained it to me.
是由于某种磁悬浮的影响
Some kind of maglev effect.
因为unobtanium是一种类似超导的物质
Because unobtanium is a superconductor… or something.
欢迎光临营地
Welcome to camp.
- 所以 我睡这里 - 好恶心
- So, this is my bunk. - This stuff is nasty.
- 诺姆 你睡下面 - 好
- Norm, go under. - All right.
格蕾丝什么都知道
Grace didn't miss a thing.
楚迪 你睡上面
Trudy, you'll take the top one.
她知道我跟上校暗中往来
She knew I was talking to the Colonel.
但她目前还需要我才能让她重回到部落
But I had what she needed, a way back in with the clan,
所以她现在对我还算客气
so she's playing nice.
好吧 杰克 左转
All right. Jake, hang a left.
你使用最后面一台连接舱
You'll be in the link at the end.
一号舱 比尤拉 她是这里最稳定的一台
Unit one. Beulah. She's the least glitchy.
酷毙了
Holy shit!
不要盯着她的眼睛看
Do not look in her eye.
伊卡兰不是马
Ikran is not horse.
一旦完成了「萨黑鲁」
Once shahaylu is made,
伊卡兰终身只会跟随一名猎人
ikran will fly with only one hunter in the whole life.
要想成为「塔龙纽」 也就是猎人
To become taronyu, hunter,
你必须选择你自己的伊卡兰
you must choose your own ikran.
同时它也要选择你
and he must choose you.
- 什么时候 - 等你准备好的时候
- When? - When you are ready.
好 影像日记第十二号
Okay. This is video log 12.
时间是晚上九点三十二分
Time's 21:32.
我非得要现在做这些吗 我真的很想睡了
Do I have to do this now? I really need to get some rack.
不行 就现在 趁热打铁
No, now. When it's fresh.
好吧 地点 棚屋
Okay, location, shack,
日子开始搞混在一起了
and the days are starting to blur together.
纳威语很难学 但是 你知道
The language is a pain, but, you know,
我觉得就像拆装武器一样
I figure it's like field-stripping a weapon.
只需要反覆地练习 反覆地练习
Just repetition, repetition.
- 眼睛 - 眼睛
- Navi. - "Nari."
- Nari. - "Narrri"!
眼睛
Narrri!
用力一点 用力一点
Txurnì'ul. Stronger.
妮特丽称呼我为「斯康」 意思是笨蛋
Neytiri calls me skxawng. It means moron.
这是很重要的
This is a very important part of it.
现在诺姆对我的态度也大有好转
Norm's attitude has improved lately.
我感受到你
I see you. I see you.
纳威语的看见不仅仅是用眼睛看见
But it's not just, "I'm seeing you in front of me, "
而是用心灵感应到你
it's "I see into you. I See you."
能和他友好相处是很不错
It's good he's back on board,
但他也认为我是个笨蛋
but he thinks I'm a skxawng, too.
「我接受你 我理解你」
"I'm accepting you. I understand you."
你得搞清楚差别？好吗
So you gotta get this, okay?
你得快点 好了吗？ 出发
I gotta run! Okay? Let's go.
我的脚变得越来越强壮
My feet are getting tougher.
我一天跑得比一天远
I can run farther every day.
我必须相信我的身体才能去做任何困难的事
I have to trust my body to know what to do.
耶 看到没有
Yeah! Check it out!
哦 妈的！
Oh, crap!
我们每天都在观察森林小径
Every day it's reading the trails,
像水坑中的足迹
the tracks at the waterhole,
察觉最微小的气味和声音
the tiniest scents and sounds.
她总是提到一种会流动的能量 万物的灵魂
She's always going on about the flow of energy, the spirits of animals.
真希望最终测验的时候
I really hope this tree-hugger crap.
没有这些锁碎的题目
isn't on the final.
这可不是单靠眼睛看和双手触摸就可以理解的
This isn't just about eye-hand coordination out there, you know.
你必须仔细倾听她所说的一切
You need to listen to what she says.
透过她的眼睛 去感受这片森林
Try to see the forest through her eyes.
对不起 这可是我的影像日记
Excuse me. This is my video log here.
跟着妮特丽学习 如果不学快一点就完蛋了
With Neytiri, it's learn fast or die.
你是在开玩笑的吧
You gotta be kidding me.
我说服莫娅让格蕾丝来到部落
I talked Mo'at into letting Grace into the village.
瞧瞧你们 都长这么高了
Look how big you are.
自从她的学校关闭后 这是她第一次回来
It's the first time since her school was closed down.
你变得好漂亮啊
You are so pretty.
去睡觉 陆战队的
Come on, Marine.
我试着用心体会这种微妙的关系
I'm trying to understand this deep connection.
人和森林的心灵感应
the people have to the forest.
她说能量就如同某种连结网路
She talks about a network of energy.
万物都是息息相关的
that flows through all living things.
她说 生命都是由万物所生成的
She says all energy is only borrowed,
总有一天 生命将回到最原始的起点
and one day you have to give it back.
你今天进入了阿凡达16个小时了
You were in 16 hours today.
你的体重不断在减少
You're still losing weight.
不行
No, you don't.
- 我要去睡一会儿 - 给我回来
- I gotta get some sleep. - Come back here.
祝好胃口
Bon appétit.
今天我杀生了
Today I made a kill.
我们还吃了它
And we ate it. At least,
我终于知道他们的食物来源了
I know where that meal came from.
那是另一个身体
Other body.
但你也要照顾这一个身体的 知道吗？
You need to take care of this body. Okay?
- 知道了吗？ 我们吃了它 - 好的 好的
- Get it? Let's eat it. - Yeah, yeah.
来 我来帮你把
Here. I'll make it easy for you.
把袋子给我
Give it to me.
- 你真邋遢 - 谢谢夸奖
- You look like crap. - Thank you.
你做事太极端了
You're burning way too hard.
把这狗屎弄走
Get rid of this shit.
然后你可以继续诉说我了
And then you can lecture me.
现在 我要跟你讲 作为你的老板
Now, I'm telling you, as your boss,
或者以后还有可能变为朋友的人 我告诉你
and as someone who might even consider being a friend someday.
我建议你坐下来待会儿
to take some down time.
麻烦你吃了它吧
Eat this, please.
相信我吧 我了解你的艰难
Trust me, I… learned the hard way.
那间学校发生过什么事 格蕾丝？
What did happen at the school, Grace?
妮特丽的姐姐 Sylwanin
Neytiri's sister, Sylwanin,
突然间再也没来上学
stopped coming to school.
她对于森林的砍伐非常气愤
She was angry about the clear-cutting.
然后有一天
And one day,
她和另一对年轻的猎人跑了进来
she and a couple of other young hunters came running in.
全身都绘上了东西
all painted up.
他们烧了一台推土机
They had set a bulldozer on fire.
那些士兵跟踪他们一直到学校
I guess they thought I could protect them.
我想他们以为我可以保护他们
The troopers pursued them to the school.
他们在门口把Sylwanin打死了
They killed Sylwanin in the doorway.
就在妮特丽面前
Right in front of Neytiri.
然后开始向其他孩子开枪
And then shot the others.
虽然大部分孩子都被我带走了
I got most of the kids out.
但他们再也没有来了
But they never came back.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
一个科学家不能有任何偏见
A scientist stays objective.
我们不能被情绪而驱动
We can't be ruled by emotion.
但我花了10年心血在那间学校
But I put 10 years of my life into that school.
他们叫我sa'nok
They called me sa'nok.
母亲
Mother.
那伤痛跟随着我到了现在
That kind of pain reaches back through the link.
我感受到你
I see you…
兄弟
…Brother.
谢谢你
…and thank you.
你的灵魂将与艾娃同在
Your spirit goes with Eywa.
你的身体将留在这里
Your body stays behind…
成为我们的一部分
…to become part of The People.
一箭毙命
A clean kill.
你已经准备好了
You are ready.
学习驾驭伊卡兰 我们称之为「女妖翼兽」
Learning to ride an ikran, we call them banshees,
是每一位猎人都必经的考验
is the test every young hunter has to pass.
想要完成这项考验
But to do that,
你必须要先抵达女妖翼兽的栖息地
you gotta go where the banshees are.
呜哇
Oo-rah.
现在呢？
Now what?
杰克·萨利先来
Jakesully will go first.
现在你要选择你的伊卡兰 你要用内心去感受
Now you choose your ikran. This you must feel inside.
如果它也选择你的话
If he also chooses you,
你的动作要快 像我示范的那样
move quick like I showed.
你只有一次机会 杰克
You will have one chance, Jake.
我要怎么知道它选上我
How will I know if he chooses me?
它会试图杀掉你
He will try to kill you.
太好了
Outstanding.
我们来跳舞吧
Let's dance.
那个笨蛋快没命了
That moron's going to die.
不要害怕 战士
Don't be afraid, warrior.
快点缔结关系
Make the bond!
不
No!
杰克
Jake!
萨黑鲁 杰克
Shahaylu, Jake.
萨黑鲁！
Shahaylu!
安静点！
Stop!
太好了 没错 你是我的了？
Yeah, that's right. You're mine. Huh?
第一次飞行认定关系 你不能等
First flight seals the bond. You cannot wait.
- 想着飞 - 飞
- Think, "Fly!" - Fly?
该死的！
God damn!
喔 完了！
Oh, shit!
闭嘴 直飞！
Shut up and fly straight!
这还差不多 向左转！
That's it. Bank left!
保持水平 这就对了
Level out! That's it.
耶 杰克·萨利！
Jake Sully!
嗨！
Hey!
我们走吧！
Let's go!
耶 宝贝 我成功了！
Yeah, baby, I got this!
哦 该死的！
Oh, shit!
我骑马的技术可能不怎么样
I may not be much of a horse guy,
但骑这个我可是天生的高手
but I was born to do this.
耶
Yeah!
- 我像这样飞过来 你像这样 - 好
- I came like this. This you. - Yeah, yeah.
顺着风转弯 可以转的更快
I turn. I feel the wind. I turn very strong.
明白 我转得太僵硬了
Look, yeah, see, I banked so hard…
灵魂之树
The Tree of Souls.
这是他们最神圣的地方
It's their most sacred place.
看那漩涡磁流 还有这些图像？
See the Flux Vortex in these false color images?
就是那东西把我的仪器弄挂的
Yeah, that's what messes up my instruments.
那里有一些很有趣的生物现象
There is something really interesting going on in there biologically.
我很想冒死去取点样本
I would die to get samples.
外人可是严格禁止进入的
Outsiders are strictly forbidden.
你小子真幸运
You lucky swine.
好！
Hell, yeah!
我曾是一个冷血的空中猎人 从空中播撒死亡
I was a stone-cold aerial hunter. Death from above.
但问题是 你也有可能是别人的猎物
Only problem is, you're not the only one.
俯冲！
Dive!
快走！ 快走！
Go, go!
跟我来
Follow me!
我们的人管它叫做「狮鹰翼兽」
Our guys call it a Great Leonopteryx.
它是托鲁克 最终阴影
It is Toruk. Last Shadow.
有道理 她会是你死亡前看到的最后影像
Yeah, right. It's the last one you ever see.
我的曾曾祖父是托鲁克玛克托
My grandfather's grandfather was Toruk Macto.
「魅影骑士」
Rider of Last Shadow.
他骑这个
He rode this?
托鲁克选择了他
Toruk chose him.
根据我们族人的传说
It has only happened five times.
历史上只发生过五次
since the time of the First Songs.
- 那还真是悠久 - 是的
- That's a long time. - Yes.
魅影骑士非常伟大
Toruk Macto was mighty.
他曾在苦难时期把所有部落凝聚起来
He brought the clans together in a time of great sorrow.
每个纳威人都听过这个故事
All Na'vi people know the story.
每一件事好像都颠倒了过来
Everything is backwards now.
彷彿那里才是真实的世界
Like out there is the true world.
而这里反倒变成了一场梦
and in here is the dream.
很难相信日子才过了三个月
It's hard to believe it's only been three months.
我几乎记不起以前的生活
I can barely remember my old life.
我甚至忘了我是谁
I don't know who I am anymore.
你没在森林里迷失了自我吧
Haven't gotten lost in the woods, have you?
距离你上一次的报告
Your last report was.
已经是两个星期前的事了
more than two weeks ago.
我都开始怀疑你是不是放弃了！
I'm starting to doubt your resolve!
在我看来 是时候终止这项任务了
The way I see it, it's time to terminate the mission.
不 我可以完成
No, I can do this.
你已经完成了
You already have.
你给了我很有用的情报
You give me good, usable intel.
这个叫灵魂之树的地方
This Tree of Souls place.
对 我有这个在手
Yeah, I got them by the balls.
作战时就可以逼他们就范
with that when this turns into a shit fight,
战争不可避免
which it will. Yeah.
是时候归队了
Now it's time to come in.
对了
By the way,
你可以重新站起来了
you gonna get your legs back.
我已经帮你取得了公司的同意 全都搞定了
Yeah. I got your corporate approval. It's a done deal.
你今晚就可以搭船回家了
Gonna have you on a shuttle tonight.
我是个说话算话的人
I'm a man of my word.
我必须把它完成
I gotta finish this.
还有最后一件事
There's one more thing.
一个仪式 这是成为纳威人的最后阶段
Ceremony. It's the final stage of becoming a man.
如果做到了 我就会成为他们的一份子
If I do it, I'm one of them.
他们就会信任我
And they'll trust me.
我就可以跟他们谈搬迁的事宜
And I can negotiate the terms of their relocation.
那么 你最好把它搞定 下士
Well, then, you'd better get it done, Corporal.
纳威人说 每个人出生后都会经过两次洗礼
The Na'vi say that every person is born twice.
第二次
The second time is.
就是当你在族人面前取得一个永久的地位
when you earn your place among The People forever.
你现在是奥玛蒂卡亚族之子
You are now a son of the Omaticaya.
你是我们的一份子了
You are part of The People.
跟我来 来
Come. Come.
这是我们族人祈祷的地方
This is a place for prayers to be heard.
有时候你的祈祷也会灵验
And sometimes answered.
我们称这些树为「奥特拉亚莫克力」
We call these trees Utraya Mokri.
声音之树
The Tree of Voices.
先灵之声
The voices of our ancestors.
我可以听见他们
I can hear them.
杰克 他们还活着
They live, Jake,
与艾娃同在
within Eywa.
你现在是奥玛蒂卡亚族人了
You are Omaticaya now.
你可以拥有属于你自己的弓箭
You may make your bow from the wood of Hometree.
然后选择一位女子
And you may choose a woman.
我们有很多好女人
We have many fine women.
尼娜唱歌最好听
Ninat is the best singer.
但我不想要尼娜
But I don't want Ninat.
佩拉是位好猎人
Beyral is a good hunter.
对 她真是位好猎人
Yeah, she is a good hunter.
但我已经选择了
I've already chosen.
不过这位女子也必须选择我
But this woman must also choose me.
她早也已经选择好了
She already has.
我和你在一起了 杰克
I am with you now, Jake.
我们此生永不分离
We are mated for life.
杰克 你在搞什么？
What the hell are you doing, Jake?
杰克
Ma Jake!
别忘了阶段整合
Don't forget your phase integration.
- 杰克 - 不 不 按下中间钮
- Jake! - No, no, the middle button.
- 你得吃点东西 - 对 就是那个
- You gotta eat something. - Yeah, there you go.
杰克 醒一醒啊 杰克！ 求你！
Jake! Jake. Wake up! Jake, please!
别逼我强喂瘸子
Don't make me force-feed a cripple.
格蕾丝 我不想 嘿！
Grace, I don't want… Hey!
杰克！
Jake!
好
Okay.
我吃饱了 走吧
Here. I'm done. Let's go.
你上次洗澡是什么时候
And when was the last time you took a shower?
- 我不需要洗澡 - 天哪 陆战队的
- I don't need a shower. - Jesus, Marine.
杰克
Jake!
杰克！ 醒醒啊！ 杰克！ 醒醒啊！
Jake! Wake up! Jake! Wake up!
嘿！
Hey!
停下来！ 停下来！
Stop! Stop!
- 杰克！ - 回去 停下来！
- Jake! - Go back, stop!
嘿 老板
Hey, boss.
嘿！
Hey!
- 怎么了！ - 有个纳威人
- What? - I got a native.
对着机器乱吼乱叫 他挡到我的路了
doing the funky chicken here. He's blocking my blade.
继续开 他会闪开的
Well, keep going. He'll move.
这些人必须明白 我们是不会停的
These people have to learn that we don't stop.
继续 走 走 走
Come on, go, go, go.
停下来！ 嘿！
Stop! Hey!
快走！ 快走！
Go! Go!
瞧 看到没有？ 他闪开了吧
There, see? He moved.
老兄 老兄！ 别！
Dude, dude. Whoa, dude! Dude, no!
哦 我看不见了
I'm blind.
- 杰克！ - 妮特丽！
- Jake! - Neytiri!
这边 快跑！
Here, come on!
定格 就在那里
Freeze it right there.
拉近 放大
Scale up. Enhance.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
真是难以置信
Unbelievable.
- 给我找个飞行员来 - 是 长官
- Get me a pilot. - Yes, sir.
苏泰 将带领我们战斗
Tsu'tey will lead the war party.
别这么做
Stop please!
这将会使事情变更糟
This will only make it worse.
这里没有你说话的地方
You do not speak here!
我们要打得他们满地找牙
We will strike them in the heart.
苏泰 不要这样做
Tsu'tey! Don't do this.
- 你 - 听着 兄弟
- You! - Listen. Brother…
- 你跟这女人交配了？ - 喔 坏了
- You mated with this woman? - Oh, shit.
这是真的吗？
Is this true?
我们在艾娃的面前互定终身 已成定局了
We are mated before Eywa. It is done.
兄弟 听我说
Brother, please.
不要去攻击天空人
Do not attack the Sky People.
你那样做会害死很多同胞的
Many Omaticaya will die if you do.
你才不是我的兄弟！
You are not my brother!
但我也不是你的敌人！
And I am not your enemy!
我们的敌人就在外面 他们的火力很强大！
The enemy is out there, and they are very powerful!
前进！ 前进！ 前进！
Go! Go! Go!
- 让我跟他们谈 - 不用谈了
- I can talk to them. - No more talk.
苏泰
Tsu'tey!
我是奥玛蒂卡亚族人 我是你们的一份子
I am Omaticaya. I am one of you.
我有说话的权利
And I have the right to speak.
我有些事情要说
I have something to say…
对你们每一个人说
…to all of you.
这些话在我心里已经憋了很久
The words are like stones in my heart.
长官 我很抱歉 别！别！不要！ 住手！
Sir, I'm sorry. No, no, no! Hold on!
你不能干扰连线！
You can't interrupt a link in progress!
这么做很危险
It's very dangerous!
格蕾丝
Grace!
糟糕
Oh, no.
- 等等 - 你给我趴下
- Wait! - Stay down, sir.
好 听着
Okay. Look…
我是被派到这里来
I was sent here to…
看到了吧
You see?
他只不过是个使用假身的魔鬼 他不能活着
It is a demon in a false body.
- 你他妈的疯了吗 - 你太过分了
- Are you out of your goddamn mind? - You crossed the line.
把这家伙给我带走
Wheel this meat out of here.
杰克 到底发生了什么事？
Jake! What the hell is going on here?
你让我真失望 小子
You let me down, son.
你是怎么了 你
So, what,
在这里找到了个土著女朋友
you find yourself some local tail.
就忘了你是站在哪一边的了？
and you just completely forget what team you're playing for?
帕克 还有时间挽回局面
Parker, there is time to salvage the situation.
- 帕克 - 闭上你的鸟嘴！
- Parker… - Shut your pie hole!
不然怎样 脍子手 你要对我开枪吗？
Or what, Ranger Rick? You gonna shoot me?
- 我可以那样做 - 你需要管好你的狗
- I could do that. - You need to muzzle your dog.
大家都静一静好吗？
Yeah, can we just take this down a couple of notches, please?
你不是说要保障你的人都活着吗？
You say you want to keep your people alive?
先听听她的说法吧
You start by listening to her.
那些树对于奥玛蒂卡亚族人来说
Those trees were sacred to the Omaticaya.
是你无法想像的那种神圣
in a way you can't imagine.
真的吗？
You know what?
好比是拿根木杖对天空挥两下
You throw a stick in the air around here,
然后就会降下什么鬼圣物这样吗
it's gonna land on some sacred fern,
- 老天 - 我说的不是
- for Christ's sake! - I'm not talking.
那些灵异的巫术
about some kind of pagan voodoo here. I'm talking about something real,
我说的是真实存在的东西
something measurable in the biology of the forest.
用来解释生物与森林之间的关系
Something measurable in the biology of the forest.
那到底是什么东西？
Which is what, exactly?
就我们所知
What we think we know.
在树与树根之间都有着某种
is that there is some kind of electrochemical communication.
类似电流的讯息传递
between the roots of the trees,
就好像神经细胞组织那样
like the synapses between neurons.
每一棵树之间都有着成千成万个不同的连结点
And each tree has ten-to-the-fourth connections to the trees around it.
潘多拉星球有上亿万棵树
And there are ten-to-the-twelfth trees on Pandora.
我想就是指这里有很多树
Which is a lot, I'm guessing.
这比人脑还要复杂
It's more connections than the human brain.
明白吗 这像是一种网路
Get it? It's a network.
一种全球网路 纳威人可以登录进去
It's a global network, and the Na'vi can access it.
他们可以上传和下载讯息 甚至储存
They can upload and download data. Memories.
你刚刚毁掉的就是一个网站
At sites like the one you just destroyed.
没错
Yes!
你们到底在外面嗑了什么东西
What the hell have you people been smoking out there?
那不过只是一些该死的树而已！
They're just goddamn trees!
帕克 你要搞清楚
You need to wake up, Parker.
不 你才给我搞清楚
No. You need to wake up.
这个星球的资源不是在地下
The wealth of this world isn't in the ground.
而是在我们的周围
It's all around us.
纳威人知道这一点 他们会誓死捍卫它
The Na'vi know that, and they are fighting to defend it.
如果你想跟他们共同享有这个世界
If you want to share this world with them,
你就要去了解他们
you need to understand them.
我要说 我们已经了解得够多了
I'd say we understand them just fine,
这还真得多亏了杰克
thanks to Jake here.
嘿 博士 过来看看
Hey, Doc, come take a look.
他们绝不会放弃他们的家园
They're not gonna give up their home.
他们不会接受任何条件
They're not gonna make a deal.
他们要什么 清淡啤酒
For what? Lite beer?
蓝色牛仔裤？
And blue jeans?
他们根本就不需要我们的东西
There's nothing that we have that they want.
我们所做的一切根本是在浪费时间
Everything they sent me out here to do is a waste of time.
他们绝不会离开家园树的
They're never gonna leave Hometree.
既然达不成协议
So, since a deal can't be made,
我觉得这事就变得简单多了
I guess things get real simple.
杰克 谢了 我真的很兴奋
Jake, thanks. I'm getting all emotional.
兴奋到我都想给你一个热吻
I might just give you a big wet kiss.
跟我说一下状况 莱尔
Talk to me, Lyle.
看来他们首先是用女妖翼兽来进攻的
It looks like they hit it with banshees first.
看到那个角被浸透过没有？
See the angle's steep?
他们放火烧了AMP装甲
They set the ampsuit on fire.
驾驶员成烤土豆了
Driver's toast.
其他队员呢？
The rest of the squad?
6具尸体 全都在这里了
Six bodies. That's all of them.
设备损失
The equipment's totaled.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ.
我会尽量把伤害降到最低
I'll do it with minimal casualties to the indigenous.
我会先用催泪瓦斯把他们给赶走
I'll drive them out with gas first.
这应该会人道一点
It'll be humane.
大概吧
More or less.
好吧 开始干吧
All right, let's pull the trigger.
快点 快点准备好 出发
Come on, people. Let's get it packed, let's go.
我想你知道的 他从来都没想过我们会成功
You know, they never even wanted us to succeed.
他们故意用推土机去铲别人的圣地
They bulldozed a sacred site on purpose.
惹毛别人
to trigger a response.
然后编造借口 发动战争
Just fabricating this war.
去得到他们想要的东西
to get what they want.
掠夺就是这样
This is how it's done.
当别人拥有你想要的东西
When people are sitting on shit that you want,
你就视他们为敌人
you make them your enemy.
然后顺理成章的把东西抢过来
Then you're justified in taking it.
夸奇上校刚刚召集了武装直升机
Quaritch is rolling the gunships.
他要去攻击家园树
He's gonna hit Hometree.
我的天
My God.
奥古斯汀博士 你不能到这里来
Dr. Augustine! You cannot be up here!
让开
Back off!
帕克 等等 停下
Parker. Wait. Stop.
他们都是人 你却要
These are people you're about to…
- 不 不 不 - 我叫你走开！
- No. No, no, no, no. - I said back off!
他们只是一群浑身叮满苍蝇住在树上的野蛮人！
They're fly-bitten savages that live in a tree!
懂吗 看看四周
All right? Look around!
我不太清楚你是怎么想
I don't know about you,
不过我看到了很多很多的树 他们可以搬走！
but I see a lot of trees! They can move!
你们这些家伙能不能
Can you guys just please…
是的 首长
Yes, sir.
家园树里有很多家庭 有小孩 有婴儿
There are families in there. There are children. Babies.
你要杀小孩吗？
Are you gonna kill children?
你不会真的想这么做 相信我
You don't want that kind of blood on your hands. Believe me.
让我去说服他们
Just let me try to talk them out.
他们信任我
They trust me.
快点准备 我们立刻出发
Calibrate fast. We're going in, right now.
三号 四号就绪
Calibrating three and four.
- 启动程序 - 倒数三十秒
- Run sequence. - Initiating. Thirty seconds.
听着 我给你一个小时
Listen to me. You've got one hour.
如果你不想让你的女朋友一起陪葬的话
Unless you want your girlfriend in there when the ax comes down,
就叫他们赶紧滚蛋 就一个小时
you get them to evacuate. One hour.
父亲
Father!
母亲
Mother!
埃图康 我有话要说
Eytukan, I have something to say.
请听他说
Listen!
说吧 杰克·萨利
Speak, Jakesully.
灾难就要降临了
A great evil is upon us…
天空人正往这里来
The Sky People are coming…
摧毁家园树
…to destroy Hometree.
告诉他们 天空人马上就要来了
Look, tell them they're gonna be here soon.
大家不离开就会没命
You have to leave, or you're gonna die.
你确定吗
Are you certain of this?
是他们派我来学习你们的文化
Look, they sent me here to learn your ways.
以便有一天我可以传达这个讯息的时候
so one day I could bring this message.
你们才会相信我
and that you would believe it.
杰克 你在说什么？
What are you saying, Jake?
你早就知道会发生这种事
You knew this would happen?
是的
Yes.
听着 一开始我只是奉命行事
Look, at first it was just orders,
但后来 一切都变了
and then everything changed.
好吗 我爱上了
Okay? I fell in love.
我爱上了这片森林 爱上了奥玛蒂卡亚族人
I fell in love with the forest and with the Omaticaya people.
还有你
And with you.
- 我当初信任你 - 我爱上了你
- I trusted you. - With you. With you.
- 我是那么的相信你 - 请你现在相信我
- I trusted you! - Trust me now, please.
你永远不会成为我们的一分子
You will never be one of The People!
- 我不应该 - 我们试着阻止他们了
- I shouldn't have… - We tried to stop them!
- 妮特丽 别这样 - 永远不会
Neytiri, please! Please.
把他们绑起来
Bind them.
快点走吧
Leave now!
你们必须离开 他们就要到了
You have to go. They're coming!
一分钟后抵达目标
Time on target, one mike.
收到 目标进入视线
Copy. We have a visual.
收到 保持航向 方位0-3-0
Roger that. Stay on heading 030.
明白 方位0-3-0
Roger, 030.
- 赶快逃进森林里去 - 他们快到了！
- Run to the forest! - They're coming!
他们会摧毁这个地方
They will destroy this place.
妮特丽 你得立刻离开
Neytiri, you must go now!
赶快逃进森林里去 快走
Run to the forest! Run!
跑 跑
Run! Run!
不要犹豫了
Have no fear.
不 该死的 快走啊！
No! God damn it, run!
骑上伊卡兰
Take the ikran…
从空中发动攻击
…attack from above.
还真是他妈的一颗大树
That is one big damn tree.
瞧瞧这个 看来我们的谈判失败了
Well, well, well. I'd say diplomacy has failed.
好啦 各位 开工吧！
All right, people, let's get this done!
我要所有的催泪瓦斯弹都对准了入口
I want every gas round you got right in the front door.
了解 CS.40催泪瓦斯弹准备发射
Roger. CS.40's going hot.
- 开火 - 发射
- Fire. - Firing.
中了 你真是神枪手
Bingo. Mighty good shooting, ace.
长官 他们开火了
Sir, they've opened fire.
你不是在开玩笑的吧
You've got to be kidding me!
这些野蛮人怎么还搞不清楚状况
These dumb bastardsain't getting the message.
给他们一点颜色瞧瞧
All right, let's turn up the heat.
- 改用燃烧弹！ - 改用燃烧弹
- Switch incendiaries! - Switching incendiaries.
开火
Fire.
不
No!
大家快到森林里去
Get everyone to the forest.
蟑螂就是这么驱散的
And that's how you scatter the roaches.
妮特丽
Neytiri!
我们得想办法离开 他们要炸掉树干了！
We gotta move! He's gonna blow the columns!
我的天
My God!
- 莫娅 不要！ - 如果你是我们的一分子
- Mo'at! No! - If you are one of us,
请你帮帮我们
help us.
所有单位 改用导弹
All call signs, switch missiles.
把导弹都给我对准西边树干
Give me HE's at the base of the west columns.
这边
This way!
骑士小队改用导弹
Rider section, switch missiles.
- 一号准备完成 - 二号完成
- One's good. - Two's rocks up.
- 三号完成 - 耶 尝尝这个！
- Three's up. - Yeah, baby, get some!
指挥机 战机待命中
Charlie Oscar, Gunrunner standing by.
- 把它轰垮 - 准许发射
- Bring it down. - Cleared hot.
格蕾丝 快点！
Come on, Grace, move!
趴下 快趴下！
Down! Head down!
快 快 趴下
Come on, come on! Down!
- 命中 - 确实命中目标
- Solid hits. - Solid rocks on target.
去他妈的
Screw this.
唉！ 你在搞什么啊
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
我可不是为了干这种混账事来这里的！
I didn't sign up for this shit!
重复 火力全开
Repeat. Ripple fire.
快跑！ 快！ 快！
Go! Go! Go!
不 不 回来 回来
No, no, get back! Back!
快点 快 走 走
Come on! Come on, move! Move!
干得漂亮 各位 今晚的庆功宴算我的
That's good work, people. First round's on me tonight.
全体回航吧
Let's boogie.
飞龙突击艇左转弯 返航回基地
Dragon coming left, heading home.
炮艇机左转弯
Gunrunner coming left.
- 雷电小队收到 - 骑士小队收到
- Thunder copies. - Rider section copies.
父亲！
Father!
女儿
Daughter…
拿着 我的 弓箭
take… my… bow.
保护族人
Protect The People.
妮特丽！
Neytiri!
- 对不起 对不起 - 走开
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - Get away.
给我滚开！
Get away!
离我远远的！
Get away from here!
永远别再回来！
Never come back!
把机器停了
Pull the plug.
你不能！ 不 你不能这么做！
No, you can't do that!
你不能这么做！
You can't do that!
- 冷静！ 冷静下来！ - 不！ 拜托！
- Calm down! Calm down! - No! Please!
我原本梦想成为带来和平的战士
I was a warrior who dreamed he could bring peace.
但很残酷的是 你终究必须回到现实
Sooner or later, though, you always have to wake up.
我们走！
Let's go!
把他放下！
Put him down!
你这个杀人凶手！
You murderer!
过得如何啊 兄弟 好久不见
What's going on, brother? Long time no see.
嘿
Hey.
我个人认为这些环保叛徒根本没资格享受牛排
Personally, I don't feel these tree-hugging traitors deserve steak.
牛排 太扯了 让我瞧瞧
They get steak? That's bullshit. Let me see that.
你知道这是什么 趴下
Yeah. You know what that is. Down.
- 楚迪 - 五体投地
- Trudy! - All the way down.
麦克斯
Max!
楚迪 发动直升机！ 快！
Trudy, fire up the ship! Go!
拿着
Here.
- 安全 快走 - 给你
- Clear. Come on. - Here you go.
麦克斯 你留下来
Max, stay here.
我需要一个能信任的内应
I need someone on the inside I can trust.
好 走吧
Okay. Go.
安全
Clear.
快点 宝贝
Come on, baby.
上校？ 长官？ 我这里有状况
Colonel? Sir? I got a situation here.
大力神1-6号未经许可擅自启动引擎
It's Samson 1-6. Unauthorized engine start.
三！
Three!
快点！
Come on!
戴上滤气面罩！
Mask on!
有毒气 有毒气 有毒气！
Gas, gas, gas!
有人在向我们开火！ 快点走！
I'm taking fire! Let's go!
抓住我的手！ 快 大家都进来了 我们走吧！
Grab my hand! Come on, we're in. Let's go!
快点 快走 快走！ 快！
Come on, let's go! Let's go, go!
上校
Colonel!
- 耶！ 耶！ - 太好了！ 漂亮！
- Yeah! Yeah! - All right! Yes!
- 狗屎 - 大家都还好吗？
- Crap. - Everybody all right back there?
哦 是的 宝贝！
Oh, yeah, baby!
- 诺姆 你呢？ - 没问题！
- Norm, you good? - Yeah!
倒霉 我挨了一枪
This is gonna ruin my whole day.
- 格蕾丝中弹了！ - 什么？
- Grace is hit! - What?
- 快拿急救箱 - 急救箱！
- Get the trauma kit. - Trauma kit!
压住伤口 格蕾丝
Keep the pressure on, Grace.
急救箱在前面的舱壁上
Trauma kit's forward, on the bulkhead.
- 格蕾丝 撑着点 - 不要紧 我没事
- Hang on, Grace. - Doesn't matter. It's fine.
- 可以了 - 吊起来吧！
- You're good to go. - Take it up!
站稳了 我开始起吊了
Hold on. I'm pulling pitch.
没有问题
You're clear!
一直向北飞 到深山里去
Just keep going north. Get us deep in the mountains.
收到
Copy that.
诺姆 你那里还好吗？
Norm, you all good up there?
很好 没问题
Yep! Still here.
至少他们无法跟踪我们到这儿来
Well, at least they can't track us up here.
至少到不了电磁旋涡这里
Not this far into the Vortex.
灵魂树一带最强烈 对吗？
It's strongest at the Tree of Souls, right?
没错
Yeah.
好极了 我们就去那里
Good. 'Cause that's where we're going.
好疼
Ouch.
你这个大孩子
You big baby.
我们在转移
We're moving.
我这就去找人救你 格蕾丝
I'm gonna get you some help, Grace.
我是科学家 记得吗？
I'm a scientist, remember?
我不相信童话故事
I don't believe in fairy tales.
他们会治好你的
The People can help you.
我知道
I know it.
他们为什么要帮我们？
Why would they help us?
纳威人说 艾娃会保护他们
The People say Eywa will provide.
没有家园 没有希望
With no home, no hope,
他们就只剩下一个地方可以去了
there was only one place they could go.
准备就绪
Link's running.
- 杰克 你有什么计划？ - 我没有计划
- What's the plan here, Jake? - There's no plan.
苏泰现在是酋长了
Tsu'tey is Olo'eyktan now.
他是不会让你接近那里的
He's not gonna let you near that place.
我总得试试
I gotta try.
开始
Launching.
放逐者
Outcast.
叛徒
Betrayer.
外星人
Alien.
我在这里 没有任何地位
I was in the place the eye does not see.
我们需要彼此的帮助
I needed their help, and they needed mine.
但要再度面对他们
But to ever face them again,
我必须重新改变他们对我的看法
I was gonna have to take it to a whole new level.
人这一辈子有时就得靠一次疯狂的举动
Sometimes your whole life boils down to one insane move.
我们要去做一件事
There's something we gotta do.
你肯定不会喜欢的
You're not gonna like it.
我认为 托鲁克是天上最可怕的飞兽
The way I had it figured, Toruk is the baddest cat in the sky.
没人敢攻击它
Nothing attacks him.
放松 兄弟
Easy, boy.
所以它怎么会往上看呢？
So why would he ever look up?
但是 这只是我的猜测
But that was just a theory.
魅影骑士
Toruk Macto?
我感受到你
I See you.
我很害怕 杰克
I was afraid, Jake.
为我的族人担心
For my people.
但现在我不再害怕了
I'm not anymore.
苏泰 阿特尤之子
Tsu'tey, son of Ateyo…
我站在你面前
…I stand before you…
随时准备为奥玛蒂卡亚族效劳
…ready to serve the Omaticaya people.
你是酋长 也是位伟大的战士
You are Olo'eyktan, and you are a great warrior.
没有你我办不到
I can't do this without you.
魅影骑士
Toruk Macto,
我愿意和你一起飞翔
I will fly with you.
我的朋友快死了
My friend is dying.
格蕾丝快死了
Grace is dying.
我请求艾娃帮助她
I beg the help of Eywa.
看看我们在哪里 格蕾丝
Look where we are, Grace.
我得采集一些样本
I need to take some samples.
艾娃也许会选择保存她的灵魂
The Great Mother may choose to save all that she is.
转移到这个身体
in this body.
这有可能吗
Is that possible?
她必须通过艾娃之眼的考验 然后再回来
She must pass through the eye of Eywa and return.
但是 杰克·萨利
But, Jakesully,
她非常虚弱
she is very weak.
坚持住 格蕾丝 他们会把你治好的
Hang on, Grace. They're gonna fix you up.
万灵之母 请倾听我们的祈祷
Hear us please, All Mother.
救救她吧 艾娃
Eywa, help her.
我们请您接收这个灵魂
Take this spirit into you…
让她重回我们身边
…and breathe her back to us.
让她的生命得以延续
Let her walk among us…
以一个真正纳威人的身份活在我们之间
…as one of The People.
杰克
Jake.
格蕾丝
Grace.
我看到艾娃了 杰克
I'm with her, Jake.
她是真的！
She's real!
格蕾丝？ 格蕾丝 别 格蕾丝！
Grace? Grace, please. Grace!
怎么回事？
What's happening?
这是怎么回事？
格蕾丝！
Grace!
发生什么事了？
What's happening?
有用吗？
Did it work?
她的伤势太严重了 已经太迟了
Her wounds were too great. It was not enough time.
她跟艾娃在一起了
She is with Eywa now.
请你允许 我现在有话要说
With your permission, I will speak now.
恳请你为我翻译
You would honor me by translating.
天空人传达一个信息给我们
The Sky People have sent us a message.
他们可以为所欲为
that they can take whatever they want.
任谁都阻止不了
and no one can stop them.
但我们要传达一个信息给他们
Well, we will send them a message.
我们将御风飞翔
You ride out as fast as the wind can carry you.
我们将集合全部的部落一同作战
You tell the other clans to come.
告诉他们魅影骑士在召唤他们
You tell them Toruk Macto calls to them.
我们现在就出发！
And you fly now with me!
我的兄弟们 姐妹们
My brothers! Sisters!
我们要让天空人知道
And we will show the Sky People.
他们不可以为所欲为
that they cannot take whatever they want,
因为这里是
and that this,
是我们的家园！
this is our land!
出发！
Yah!
我们走遍世界各地
We rode out to the four winds.
在平原上找到了马族部落
To the horse clans of the plain.
把他们赶回去
Back to the stars!
到东海岸边找到了伊卡兰族
To the ikran people ofthe Eastern Sea.
为了我们的子孙后代
For our children's children!
魅影骑士的召唤让所有人团结在一起
When Toruk Macto called them, they came.
我们出发
Yah!
这个基地的每个人
Everyone on this base, every one of you,
都在为生存努力
is fighting for survival.
这是不争的事实！
That's a fact!
现在外面有一大群纳威人正在集结
There's an aboriginal horde out there.
准备攻击
massing for an attack.
根据卫星照片显示
Now, these orbital images tell me.
这些纳威人 一天之内就从几百人
that the hostiles' numbers have gone from a few hundred.
增加到两千多人
to well over 2, 000 in one day.
而且人数还在增加当中
And more are pouring in.
一周后 将会达到两万人
In a week's time, there could be 20, 000 of them.
那时 他们会冲破我们的外围防线
At that point, they will overrun our perimeter.
但我们不会让这种事情发生
Well, that's not gonna happen!
我们唯一的办法就是先发制人
Our only security lies in pre-emptive attack.
我们将以其人之道还治其人之身
We will fight terror with terror.
那些纳威人相信他们的家园
Now, the hostiles believe that this mountain stronghold of theirs.
受到了他们的
is protected by their…
他们的神灵保佑
Their deity.
那么当我们摧毁它的时候
And when we destroy it,
我们会在他们的记忆里深深的烙上一个教训
we will blast a crater in their racial memory so deep.
让他们永远再也不敢接近
that they won't come.
离这里方圆一千公里的地方
within 1, 000 klicks of this place ever again.
而这件事也将成为不变的事实
And that, too, is a fact.
对 没错
Yeah! Yeah.
杰克 这里很夸张 几乎全体总动员
Jake, it's crazy here. It's full mobilization.
他们要把飞行器变成轰炸机
They're rigging the shuttle as a bomber.
他们在运输船上装满了大堆
They've got these huge pallets.
用来炸矿坑用专用的炸药
of mine explosives.
准备用来摧毁什么
It's for some kind of shock-and-awe campaign.
这些人全都疯了
Fricking daisy cutters!
夸奇上校接管一切
Quaritch has taken over.
现在全部都听他号令 谁也没办法阻止他
He's rolling, and there's no stopping him.
- 什么时候开始！ - 明天早上六点
- When? - 06:00 tomorrow.
- 麦克斯！ 麦克斯！ - 我不能再说了
- Max! Max! - I gotta go.
我们玩完了
We're screwed!
我原先还以为能有个什么计划
And I was hoping for some sort of tactical plan.
能够全身而退的
that didn't involve martyrdom.
我们要用弓箭对抗武装飞机
We're going up against gunships with bows and arrows.
现在外面有十五个部落
I have 15 clans out there.
超过两千名战士
That's over 2, 000 warriors.
我们清楚这些山的地形
Now, we know these mountains.
我们都清楚 你也清楚 但他们不熟悉
We fly them. You fly them. They don't.
他们的电子设备在这里不管用
Their instruments won't work up here.
自动追踪导弹也没有用
Missile tracking won't work.
他们只能手动瞄准
They'll have to fire a line of sight.
如果他们攻过来 我们就有地形上的优势
If they bring the fight to us, then we have the home-field advantage.
你知道他肯定会直接轰炸灵魂之树的
You know he's gonna commit that bomber straight to the Tree of Souls.
是啊 我知道
Yeah, I know.
如果让他们到达那里 那就玩完了
If they get to the Tree of Souls, it's over.
那可是纳威人跟艾娃 他们先灵联系的地方
That's their direct line to Eywa, their ancestors.
这会毁了纳威人意志
It'll destroy them.
那我们最好别让他们得逞
Then I guess we'd better stop him.
我可能只是在和一棵树说话
I'm probably just talking to a tree right now.
但如果您真的在那里 我必须提醒您
But if you're there, I need to give you a heads-up.
如果格蕾丝和您在一起 请您看一看她的记忆
If Grace is with you, look into her memories.
看看我们来的那个世界
See the world we come from.
那里已经没有绿色的大地了
There's no green there.
他们亲手杀死了自己的母亲
They killed their Mother.
现在他们要在这里做同样的事
And they're gonna do the same here.
更多的天空人会来到这里
More Sky People are gonna come.
他们只会越来越多 而且永远不会停止
They're gonna come like a rain that never ends.
除非我们能阻止他们
Unless we stop them.
我知道您选择了我是有原因的
Look, you chose me for something.
我一定会奋起抗争
I will stand and fight.
您知道我会这样做的
You know I will.
但我真的需要您的帮助
But I need a little help here.
艾娃是不会偏袒任何一边的 杰克
Our Great Mother does not take sides, Jake.
她只维护生态的平衡
She protects only the balance of life.
我总得试一试
It was worth a try.
对！ 对！ 这就是我要的！
Yeah! Yeah! That's what I'm talking about!
对！ 对！ 这就是我要的 伙计！
Yeah! Yeah! That's what I'm talking about, man!
这是指挥机 我们将进入电磁漩涡了
This is Group Leader. We are entering the Flux Vortex.
切换到手动飞行模式
Switch to manual flight mode.
收到 手动飞行模式
Copy. Manual flight mode.
我是总指挥官
This is Papa Dragon.
我要这次任务速战速决 我赶着回家吃晚饭
I want this mission high and tight. I want to be home for dinner.
机甲小组 出发
Suit Team, go.
好吧 姑娘们 给他们好看吧
All right, ladies, let's bring the pain!
行动 行动 行动
Move, move, move!
B1-1 向左移动
Bravo 1-1, move left.
B1-1 向左移动 注意侧翼
Bravo 1-1 moving left. Watch flank.
- 保持队形 继续前进 - 收到
- Watch formation. Keep moving. - Roger that.
C2-1 注意保持距离
Charlie 2-1, watch your spacing.
收到 完毕
Copy that. Over.
看上面 注意上方 注意热能雷达
Eyes up. Check that overhead. And watch those thermal scans.
呼叫所有单位 指挥官在领队发令
All call signs, Papa has lead,
向目标推进
pushing to target.
护卫机 紧紧跟着我的航天飞机
Escorts, stay close on my shuttle.
在这我们难免有点小磕碰了
We are gonna lose some paint in here.
机枪小组 注意山边峭壁
Gun crews, keep your head on a swivel.
别大意 各位 他们就在附近
Make no mistake, people, they're out there.
好了 各位 目标出现 距离四公里
All right, people, target in sight. Range, four klicks.
女战神1-6号 准备投弹
Valkyrie 1-6, get your payload ready.
了解 准备发射
Copy. Prepare to offload.
参谋中士 炸弹就位
Staff Sergeant, stage the weapon.
推到舷梯上！快点！
Roll it to the ramp! Let's go!
停！
Hold!
C2-1 动作快点
Charlie 2-1, got big movement.
- 保持不动 - 等等 等等
- Hold position. - Hold up, hold up.
五百米处有动静
We got movement out there, 500 meters.
C2-1 保持不动
Charlie 2-1, hold position.
长官 地面有状况 正在快速接近
Sir, ground has movement! Fast approaching.
- 指挥机 这是骑士小队 - 成射击阵型！
- Charlie Oscar, Rider section. - Firing line!
目标接近中 距离四百米
Targets closing. Range, 400 meters.
能把这个弄清楚点吗？
Can't you clean it up?
不行 长官 有电磁波干扰
No, sir. It's the Flux.
兄弟 我杀条路进去 你跟在我后面
Brother, I'm gonna punch a hole. You follow me through.
所有战机 自主射击！自主射击！
All aircraft, weapons free! Weapons free!
右转 掉头
Break right. Come around.
轰掉他们！
Light them up!
分散队形 全面攻击敌人
Break formation, engage all hostiles.
吃我子弹吧！
Yeah! Get some!
蝎子炮艇机 扫荡敌人
Scorpions, pursue and destroy.
杰克？杰克 听得到吗？
Jake! Jake! You copy?
我们要撤退了！敌人火力太猛！
We're falling back! We're getting hammered!
收到 赶快离开
Copy. Get out of there.
那是他 快给我追！
That's him. Get after him!
干掉他！
Take him out!
把她轰了！
Light her up!
把她轰了
Right there!
不是只有你才有枪 混蛋
You're not the only one with a gun, bitch.
- 看住她 - 全部瞄准她
- Keep her in your sights. - Purging. Feeding the leak.
全力攻击她
Arming all pods.
这才像话！
That's it!
西子
Seyzey!
淘气鬼一号中弹 我要返航了
Rogue One is hit. I'm going in.
杰克 抱歉
Sorry, Jake.
开火
Fire.
苏泰 兄弟 你听得到吗？
Tsu'tey! Brother, do you read?
淘气鬼一号 你收得到吗？
Rogue One, you copy?
楚迪！
Trudy!
两分钟后抵达目标
Time to target, two minutes.
女战神1-6号 障碍已清除 准备开火
Valkyrie 1-6, you are cleared and hot.
收到 飞龙号 开始投弹程序
Copy, Dragon. We are starting our bomb run.
一号弹 解除保险！
Arm number one!
一号弹 保险已解除！
Number one armed!
杰克！
Ma Jake!
我听得到
I read you.
- 妮特丽 - 西子死了
- Neytiri! - Seyzey's dead.
敌人离得很近 人非常多
They are very close. They are many.
不要攻击
Do not attack.
听到了吗？妮特丽
Do you read me, Neytiri?
不要攻击
Do not attack!
快点撤退 现在就离开 这是命令
Fall back now. Get out of there! That's an order!
妮特丽！
Neytiri!
前方有动静 有动静
I got movement, I got movement.
留在原地 有东西来了
Hold position. Something's coming.
B1-1 有很大的感应 注意屏幕
Bravo 1-1, I got a big seating.Turn screens over.
有东西靠近了 距离两百米
We got movement 200 meters.
保持队形
Hold your formation.
- 准备好 - 注意侧翼
- Be ready. - Watch your flanks.
距离一百米 快速接近中
Hundred meters and closing fast.
我们得离开这里！
We gotta get out of here!
- 撤退！撤退！- 快撤！快撤！快撤！
- Fall back! Fall back! - Move! Move! Move!
撤退！快跑！快跑！
Fall back! On the run! On the run!
杰克 艾娃听到了
Jake, Eywa has heard you.
艾娃听到你了！
Eywa has heard you!
走吧
Come on!
撤退！快撤！快撤！
Fall back! Move! Move!
长官 护卫机不是被击落就是正在撤退
Sir! All escorts are down or falling back.
来结束这一切吧 飞龙号呼叫女战神1-6号
Let's get this done. Valkyrie 1-6, this is Dragon.
- 强攻目标 - 收到 强攻目标
- Press to target. - Copy. Pressing to target.
投弹倒计时三十秒
Stand by to drop, 30 seconds.
听我指令 二 一 投弹
On my mark. Two, one, mark.
投弹！ 投弹！ 投弹！ 快 快 快 快
Drop! Drop! Drop! Go, go, go, go!
顶住！
Brace!
是萨利
It's Sully.
- 戴上滤气面罩！ - 破裂警报！
- Mask on! - Breach alarm!
来啊 到爸爸这里来
Come on. Come to papa.
投降吧！ 夸奇
Give it up, Quaritch!
都结束了
It's all over.
我还有一口气在就不会结束
Nothing's over while I'm breathing.
这话正合我意
I kind of hoped you'd say that.
来吧！
Come on!
嘿 萨利 背叛自己的种族感觉怎样？
Hey, Sully, how's it feel to betray your own race?
你真以为你是他们的一份子？
You think you're one of them?
该醒来了
Time to wake up.
杰克？
Jake?
杰克
Jake.
杰克 我的杰克！
Jake! Ma Jake!
感受到你
I See you.
感受到你 兄弟
I See you, Brother.
族人安全了吗
Are The People safe?
他们安全了
They're safe.
我不能
I can't…
我不能领导他们了
I cannot lead The People.
你必需要领导他们 杰克萨利
You must lead them… Jakesully.
我不是当首领的料
I'm not officer material.
这是注定的
It is decided.
现在
Now…
完成奥玛蒂卡亚族该做的事吧
…do the duty of Olo'eyktan.
我不会杀你的
I will not kill you.
只能这样了
It is the way!
而且这对于我来说是最好的
And it is good.
我会永远记得的
I will be remembered.
我与…魅影骑士一起战斗过！
I fought… with Toruk Macto!
而且我们还是兄弟
And we were brothers.
他还是…我曾经的最终幻影
And he… was my last shadow.
外星人返回他们垂死的星球
The aliens went back to their dying world.
只有少数人被允许留下
Only a few were chosen to stay.
苦难的时代终于结束了
The time of great sorrow was ending.
人们不再需要魅影骑士了
Toruk Macto was no longerneeded.
那么 我想这应该是我最后一次的影像日记了
Well, I guess this is my last video log.
因为不论今晚发生什么 总之
'Cause whatever happens tonight, either way, I'm…
我都不会再回到这里了
I'm not gonna be coming back to this place.
看来我该走了
Well, I guess I'd better go.
我可不想错过我的派对
Yeah, I don't want to be late for my own party.
毕竟 今天是我的生日
Yeah, it's my birthday, after all.
我是杰克·萨利 录影完毕
This is Jake Sully signing off.
《阿凡达》
∮ Walking through a dream ∮
∮ 梦里穿行 ∮
∮ I see you ∮
∮ 我见到了你 ∮
∮ My light in darkness breathing hope of new life ∮
∮ 是我黑暗中的光芒 吐纳新生活的希望 ∮
∮ Now I live through you and you through me ∮
∮ 于是我中有你 你中有我 ∮
∮ Enchanting ∮
∮ 就这么着了魔 ∮
∮ I pray in my heart that this dream never end ∮
∮ 从心底祈愿 沉醉梦里不愿醒 ∮
∮ I see me through your eyes ∮
∮ 通过你的的眼睛 看到真实的自己 ∮
∮ Living through life flying high ∮
∮ 驰骋生活 朝天际飞去 ∮
∮ Your life shines the way into paradise ∮
∮ 而你照亮了通往天堂的轨迹 ∮
∮ So I offer my life ∮
∮ 把我的生命交给你 ∮
∮ I offer my love，for you ∮
∮ 把我的爱 统统给你 ∮
∮ When my heart was never open ∮
∮ 我从未开启的心 ∮
∮ And my spirit never free ∮
∮ 从未自由的魂灵 ∮
∮ To the world that you have shown me ∮
∮ 是你引领我步入新天地 ∮
∮ But my eyes could not division ∮
∮ 但我这凡胎肉眼 要怎么分辨 ∮
∮ All the colours of love and of life ever more ∮
∮ 这爱的色彩 这生命的斑斓 从今往后 ∮
∮ Evermore（I see me through your eyes） ∮
∮ 直到永远（通过你的眼睛 看到真实的自己） ∮
∮ I see me through your eyes（Living through life flying high） ∮
∮ 通过你的眼睛看到真实的自己（驰骋生活 朝天际飞去） ∮
∮ Flying high ∮
∮ 朝天际飞去 ∮
∮ Your love shines the way into paradise ∮
∮ 而你照亮了通往天堂的轨迹 ∮
∮ So I offer my life as a sacrifice ∮
∮ 我愿把自己贡献成祭品 ∮
∮ And live through your love ∮
∮ 因你的爱 我才存在 ∮
∮ And live through your life ∮
∮ 因你的生命 我才存在 ∮
∮ I see you ∮
∮ 我见到了你 ∮